<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>InfoSec Zanshin - Opinions</title><link href="https://asieira.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://asieira.github.io/feeds/opinions.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://asieira.github.io/</id><updated>2019-06-30T12:18:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Highlights from AWS re:Inforce 2019</title><link href="https://asieira.github.io/highlights-from-aws-reinforce-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-30T12:18:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T12:18:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Alexandre Sieira</name></author><id>tag:asieira.github.io,2019-06-30:/highlights-from-aws-reinforce-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A not at all impartial view of AWS' first security-only event&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I had the pleasure of attending the first ever edition of &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;AWS re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt;. In this post I'll try to summarize my impressions of the event, plus include comments and references to the main points of attention and associated documentation and related session videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Big News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-vpc-traffic-mirroring/"&gt;VPC Traffic Mirroring&lt;/a&gt;, was, in my opinion, the most market-relevant announcement at the conference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This holds the promise of allowing several security product categories to be first-class citizens in AWS for the first time. After all, AWS has full control into what integration points they allow for traditional security vendors. They are slowly adding integration points, from early days as firewalls using Marketplace AMIs to act as NAT instances to something more explicit like &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/solutions/security/waf-managed-rules"&gt;WAF Managed Rules&lt;/a&gt;. Though not explicitly associated with partners, this is still a big deal for many of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impacted product categories include Network Detection and Response, Network IDS, Network DLP and Network Forensics players. There have been a few announcements of support from vendors already, and be sure to expect more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Oh, I was wondering what all those network traffic analysis vendors were saying there were about to announce regarding AWS ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Augusto Barros (@apbarros) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/apbarros/status/1143547645648134146?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 25, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as the customer base goes, this will mostly benefit mixed environment companies. Imagine you are a large, mature organization that has a large Bro / Zeek deployment, trained personnel and lots of bespoke analytics content built on top of it. Being able to extend it to your AWS environment and leverage your existing investments is a no-brainer. I fully expect that the main driver behind AWS developing this functionality was from large representative customers in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual this is a first release and will be surely improved upon by AWS. Major caveats I noticed so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the name, collection must be set up one &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/using-eni.html"&gt;ENI&lt;/a&gt; at a time. No way to set this up across the entire VPC as you would with &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/userguide/flow-logs.html"&gt;Flow Logs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The replicated traffic generated by each instance will count against the overall bandwidth available to the instance, so do your capacity planning before deploying this in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Noteworthy Announcements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the other many new features and announcements, these were the ones that caught my attention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2019/06/aws-security-hub-now-generally-available/"&gt;Security Hub is now GA&lt;/a&gt;. Security Hub's main advantage is providing a single dashboard, event format and 3rd party integration point for your AWS security, including native services like &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/macie/"&gt;Macie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/guardduty/"&gt;Guard Duty&lt;/a&gt;. The main limitation at this point is that even though it has cross-account support, it is a per-region service. So large organizations will still have multiple "panes of glass". Hope to see AWS work on that in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kD6JdUAKdV8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2019/06/aws-control-tower-is-now-generally-available/"&gt;Control Tower is now GA&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially AWS is taking the lessons learned from &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/aws-landing-zone/"&gt;Landing Zone&lt;/a&gt;, which is a professional-services-only offer, and working towards allowing self-service automation of multi-account management as a native service. At this point it still is very much an MVP with several limitations, but should soon evolve into something invaluable so pay attention to future announcements from this team. Some of the key current limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will only work on new environments and has no way to incorporate an existing &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/organizations/"&gt;Organizations&lt;/a&gt; hierarchy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not allow you to create your own service control policies or "guard rails" as they call them in Control Tower lingo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not allow you to customize provided guard rails except for per-account On/Off status;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not have its own API, seems at this point to be basically a UI layer on top of existing services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2t-VkWt0rKk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-opt-in-to-default-encryption-for-new-ebs-volumes/"&gt;Opt-in to Default Encryption for EBS Volumes&lt;/a&gt; which should make meeting compliance requirements by default a lot easier on larger organizations. Does not handle existing unencrypted EBS volumes, but then again it's simple enough to find those with &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/encrypted-volumes.html"&gt;Config&lt;/a&gt;. This is a per-region setting, but can be automated through API calls. And most importantly, it only seems to work with &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-ec2-update-additional-instance-types-nitro-system-and-cpu-options/"&gt;Nitro&lt;/a&gt; instances:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The EBS default encryption feature for AWS uses Nitro, which means instance types that don&amp;#39;t support Nitro can no longer be launched once you enable that feature. As a side-effect, I think this means this would enforce the VPC transit encryption for your EC2s.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Piper (@0xdabbad00) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/0xdabbad00/status/1145392090806755328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;30 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Keynote Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/learn/keynote/"&gt;keynote&lt;/a&gt;, Stephen E. Schmidt (AWS VP and CISO) was the ranking executive and led the announcements. By the way don't miss out on the hilarious Corey Quinn's &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1143504072621867009"&gt;live-tweet thread&lt;/a&gt;, and you can also take a look at non-threaded posts from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fsmontenegro/status/1143508566499909637"&gt;Fernando Montenegro&lt;/a&gt; and  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlexandreSieira/status/1143514790733725700"&gt;I&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the keynote two moments caught my attention. The first was when Schmidt jabbed Azure and other competitors for the &lt;a href="https://www.datacenterknowledge.com/microsoft/azure-outage-proves-hard-way-availability-zones-are-good-idea"&gt;comparatively bad track record on availability and regional redundancy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;AWS throwing shade at competitors on region vs. availability zones &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reInforce?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#reInforce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/sg36GRjeXC"&gt;pic.twitter.com/sg36GRjeXC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexandre Sieira (@AlexandreSieira) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlexandreSieira/status/1143515510589546496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;25 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other one was having a representative from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_One"&gt;Capital One&lt;/a&gt; go on stage to claim they will be entirely cloud-based by 2020. This is a major indication (if you still needed any) of the penetration that cloud adoption is having even on compliance-heavy industries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Venue and Overall Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was held at the &lt;a href="https://www.signatureboston.com/bcec/getting-here"&gt;Boston Convention and Exhibition Center&lt;/a&gt; on June 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;. This was my first contact with this venue, but I found it perfectly accommodated an event of this size. I did, however, find a telling lack of available lodging with some astronomical hotel rates and a severe shortage of close-by AirBnb offers even registering about one month in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I fully support AWS' wonderful idea to start separate focused conferences. I attended &lt;a href="https://reinvent.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Invent&lt;/a&gt; last year in Las Vegas and it was quite simply too big to be enjoyable. I had a much better time at &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt; and was pleasantly surprised to actually make it to a few sessions as a walk-in without needing to queue a full hour in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show floor had a decent size, but a portion of the size of a single of the original rooms of the RSA Conference Expo in Moscone West or East. Still, it was a single large room containing both the sponsor booths and the AWS Developer Lounges, CTF, Breakout Session spaces and tables used for lunch, a break from it all or impromptu meetings. Again a very pleasant, spacious experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sponsors getting ready for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reinforce?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#reinforce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/oHns6yRvm8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oHns6yRvm8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Andres Riancho ☁️ (@AndresRiancho) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AndresRiancho/status/1143220457883230208?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;24 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were areas with supported charities, plus a couple of really nice touches I wish more conference organizers learn from. First, swag donation collectors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is great. Would love to see similar at all conferences. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reInforce?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#reInforce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/3Y8iJmiN4T"&gt;pic.twitter.com/3Y8iJmiN4T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chris Eng (@chriseng) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriseng/status/1143896366592274434?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;26 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is a good way to make the conference more inclusive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It’s great to see conferences doing this. This is a legit huge room with chairs and lights and carpet and everything you’d expect, not some random closet. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ReInvent?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ReInvent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/5sjd96ozdl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/5sjd96ozdl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Richard H. Boyd 🔬🎉 @ re:covery (@rchrdbyd) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rchrdbyd/status/1143879178707714049?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;26 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, my overall impression is that this was absolutely worth the time and money and I fully intend to attend &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt; again next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few other resources if you want to learn more about what went on at &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLmbt_7-buHq-sx_JFNMsbkI5qHb0gWtfZ"&gt;Youtube playlist with all the recorded sessions&lt;/a&gt; by AWS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/reinforce-2019-wrap-up-and-session-links/"&gt;Re:Inforce 2019 wrap-up and session links&lt;/a&gt; by AWS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ashishrajan/aws-re-inforce-boston-2019-aws-security-conference-recap-what-they-didnt-tell-you-on-stage-9b7ecc04ddfe"&gt;AWS Re:inforce Boston 2019— AWS Security Conference: Recap (What they didn’t tell you on stage)&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ashishrajan"&gt;Ashish Rajan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dseverski"&gt;David Severski&lt;/a&gt; for helping review an early draft of this document and providing valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="aws"></category><category term="cloud"></category><category term="event"></category><category term="reInforce"></category></entry><entry><title>Threat Intelligence Indicators are not Signatures</title><link href="https://asieira.github.io/threat-intelligence-indicators-are-not-signatures.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-13T02:03:00-02:00</published><updated>2016-02-13T02:03:00-02:00</updated><author><name>Alexandre Sieira</name></author><id>tag:asieira.github.io,2016-02-13:/threat-intelligence-indicators-are-not-signatures.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A common misunderstanding that can lead to a lot of pain.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have recently participated in a 
&lt;a href="https://www.blackhat.com/html/webcast/01212016-data-driven-threat-intelligence.html"&gt;Black Hat webcast&lt;/a&gt;
with &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/bhaskar_vk"&gt;Bhaskar Karambelkar&lt;/a&gt;, which was sponsored by 
&lt;a href="https://threatconnect.com/"&gt;ThreatConnect&lt;/a&gt;. This was related to the Black Hat 2015 session called 
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6JMEKnes-w0?list=PLnKLzDQgx6bPRfNuf3sA2Sy2JDjbcg0P5"&gt;Data-Driven Threat Intelligence: Metrics On Indicator Dissemination And Sharing&lt;/a&gt;,
which I had the pleasure to co-present with my good friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alexcpsec"&gt;Alex Pinto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the webcast, someone asked me a question about a comment I had made on how threat intelligence indicators
have multiple uses, but should not be used as signatures. One of the audience members was a bit baffled by this, and I 
am sure he is not alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's focus on automating the use of simple network indicators (IP addresses, domain names and URLs, mostly) that 
most companies will obtain from public or private threat intelligence feeds. Let me show why &lt;em&gt;using them directly as 
signatures&lt;/em&gt;, such as automatically generating IDS signatures and/or SIEM rules to alert or block on direct matches to 
them, is very troublesome. Organizations that do that will, in my experience, be most likely flooded with false 
positives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="False positives, false positives everywhere!" src="https://asieira.github.io/images/indicators-are-not-signatures/false-positives.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me go over a (far from complete) list of reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Affirming the Consequent Fallacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reliably generate an alert based on network traffic, you need to identify a situation in which the 
probability of that traffic being malicious is reasonably high. How high it needs to be depends on your organization's
tolerance to false positives. So you need to satisfy a requirement &lt;code&gt;P(malicious | traffic) &amp;gt; threshold&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Threat intelligence network indicators are data points that say &lt;em&gt;we observed a threat actor, malware or tool A generate
traffic with the characteristics M, N and O and to the external locations X, Y and Z&lt;/em&gt;. Notice how &lt;strong&gt;that alone does not 
equal any of the following claims&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most or all of the traffic with characteristics M, N or O to destinations X, Y, Z are caused by A;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A always causes traffic with characteristics M, N or O to destinations X, Y, Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you notice the mismatch? Most people will erroneously equate the claim &lt;em&gt;attackers do X&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;I can safely alert when 
X occurs in my environment&lt;/em&gt;. It's related to the 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affirming_the_consequent"&gt;affirming the consequent fallacy&lt;/a&gt;,
but it's even more striking because the feeds are not even making claim 2 above, which would be required for the classic
form of the fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an example, you could find a perfectly valid indicator saying a piece of malware uses something like
a public API from Google, Dropbox or anyone else just to verify whether it can connect to the Internet. Or it could
use some publicly available service to identify which public IP address it is reaching the Internet from, and its 
geolocation, in particular in the case of targeted attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sort of indicator can still be really useful if you are doing DFIR or hunting, as it allows you to narrow down 
compromised machines on the network, or let you know which forensic data to investigate first. But it should be obvious 
by now that generating an IDS or SIEM alert for every machine on your network that behaves in a similar manner would be 
a really bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What should I match it against?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you get an intelligence feed, it might contain indicators that are indicative of several different kinds of 
malicious behaviors. In particular the paid feeds will contain a mix of human-readable context in the form a report, 
and also the machine-readable indicators associated  with each report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that it can be very hard to automatically determine in which context each technical indicator can be
applied. In the case of IP addresses, for example, very rarely does the machine-readable data allow you to unambigously
determine something as simple as whether it is associated with &lt;em&gt;inbound&lt;/em&gt; traffic, &lt;em&gt;outbound&lt;/em&gt; traffic or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you are not familiar with the terminology, the definition of &lt;em&gt;inbound&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;outbound&lt;/em&gt; I'm referring to is the 
one used in &lt;a href="https://github.com/mlsecproject/combine"&gt;combine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/mlsecproject/tiq-test"&gt;tiq-test&lt;/a&gt;. 
Keeping  your organization as the point of reference, &lt;em&gt;inbound&lt;/em&gt; indicators would refer to traffic originating from the 
open Internet towards your organization's public assets: port scanning, credential brute forcing, automated or manual 
exploitation of Internet-facing services, etc. &lt;em&gt;Outbound&lt;/em&gt; indicators, on the other hand, would be associated with 
traffic originating from inside your organization's network towards the open Internet, such as data exfiltration, C&amp;amp;C 
traffic, downloading of malware or client-side exploits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So knowing which traffic &lt;em&gt;direction&lt;/em&gt; each indicator applies to would be the most basic way to reduce false positives,
and it is often not available for use on an automated fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;"Helpful" Feed Providers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine an analyst reverses a new malware or RAT sample and identifies that it uses a particular URL to talk back to
its creator. He will of course generate an indicator in the report for that URL. However, sometimes the feed provider
will go one step further and think "but what about people that want to match this in netflow, firewall or DNS logs?", 
and do you the favor of also generating indicators for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hostname of the URL, so you can match this on DNS;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IP addresses that hostname resolved to at the time of the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates all sort of problems and piles onto the false positives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, extracting the hostname is not always appropriate. Attackers might control the entire content served under that
hostname (think DGAs, a single compromised web server that attacker fully controls). However, it might also be a portal
with completely independent sub-sites hosted under different paths that share no infrastructure except for a load 
balancer that routes requests appropriately. Or it might be something like a Google Drive or Dropbox link, or a URL
shortener. So considering the entire domain to be compromised / malicious because of a few URLs within it is often
a step too far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's even worse when resolving domain names to IP addresses, even for domains completely dedicated to malicious 
purposes. Firstly, we know that miscreants can and will 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_flux"&gt;switch the IP addresses a domain resolves to often&lt;/a&gt;, and the IPs you
receive will most likely be outdated by the time you get to use them. Second, it's not uncommon for malicious domains
to be using a service like &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/"&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.incapsula.com/"&gt;Incapsula&lt;/a&gt; or a 
shared hosting service. So if you resolve the domain, you'll get an IP address that's shared with possibly hundreds of
benign websites. Or it could be temporarily parked at a benign IP address such as 8.8.8.8. Again, knowing that a domain 
is malicious does not necessarily mean that all of the IPs it resolves to are mostly or completely malicious as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feed providers, take note: having this extra information would be more helpful if it was possible to distinguish the 
&lt;em&gt;principled&lt;/em&gt; indicators from the &lt;em&gt;derived&lt;/em&gt; ones. But alas, this information is often not present in the 
computer-readable indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helps people realize that organizations need to put proper processes and/or automation in place to 
overcome the problems identified above if they decide to use threat intelligence indicators for detection. Even though 
threat intelligence indicators are really valuable allies to information security monitoring and DFIR initiatives, they 
are not signatures and should be used with appropriate care.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="threat intelligence"></category></entry></feed>