<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>InfoSec Zanshin - reInforce</title><link href="https://asieira.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://asieira.github.io/feeds/tag_reinforce.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://asieira.github.io/</id><updated>2019-06-28T15:17:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Highlights from AWS re:Inforce 2019</title><link href="https://asieira.github.io/highlights-from-aws-reinforce-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-28T15:17:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-28T15:17:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Alexandre Sieira</name></author><id>tag:asieira.github.io,2019-06-28:/highlights-from-aws-reinforce-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A not at all impartial view of AWS' first security-only event&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I had the pleasure of attending the first ever edition of &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;AWS re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt;. In this post I'll try to summarize my impressions of the event, plus include comments and references to the main points of attention and associated documentation and related session videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was held at the &lt;a href="https://www.signatureboston.com/bcec/getting-here"&gt;Boston Convention and Exhibition Center&lt;/a&gt; on June 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;. This was my first contact with this venue, but found it perfect to accomodate an event of this size. I did, however, found a telling lack of available lodging with some astronomical hotel rates and a severe shortage of close-by AirBnb offers even registering about one month in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I fully support AWS' wonderful idea to start separate focused conferences. I attended &lt;a href="https://reinvent.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Invent&lt;/a&gt; last year in Las Vegas and it was quite simply too big to be enjoyable. I had a much better time at &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt; and was pleasantly surprised to actually make it to a few sessions as a walk-in without needing to queue a full hour in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show floor had a decent size, but a portion of the size of a single of the original rooms of the RSA Conference Expo in Moscone West or East. Still, it was a single large room containing both the sponsor booths and the AWS Developer Lounges, CTF, Breakout Session spaces and tables used for lunch, a break from it all or impromptu meetings. Again a very pleasant, spacious experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sponsors getting ready for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reinforce?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#reinforce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/oHns6yRvm8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oHns6yRvm8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Andres Riancho ☁️ (@AndresRiancho) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AndresRiancho/status/1143220457883230208?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;24 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were areas with supported charities a few really nice touches I wish more conference organizers learn from. First, swag donation collectors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is great. Would love to see similar at all conferences. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reInforce?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#reInforce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/3Y8iJmiN4T"&gt;pic.twitter.com/3Y8iJmiN4T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chris Eng (@chriseng) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriseng/status/1143896366592274434?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;26 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is a good way to make the conference more inclusive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It’s great to see conferences doing this. This is a legit huge room with chairs and lights and carpet and everything you’d expect, not some random closet. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ReInvent?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ReInvent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/5sjd96ozdl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/5sjd96ozdl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Richard H. Boyd 🔬🎉 @ re:covery (@rchrdbyd) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rchrdbyd/status/1143879178707714049?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;26 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, my overall impression is that this was absolutely worth the time and money and I fully intend to attend &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt; again next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keynote and Announcements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/learn/keynote/"&gt;keynote&lt;/a&gt;, Stephen E. Schmidt (AWS VP and CISO) was the ranking executive and led the announcements. By the way don't miss out on the hilarious Corey Quinn's &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1143504072621867009"&gt;live-tweet thread&lt;/a&gt;, and you can also take a look at non-threaded posts from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlexandreSieira/status/1143514790733725700"&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fsmontenegro/status/1143508566499909637"&gt;Fernando Montenegro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the keynote two moments caught my attention. The first was when Schmidt jabbed Azure and other competitors for the &lt;a href="https://www.datacenterknowledge.com/microsoft/azure-outage-proves-hard-way-availability-zones-are-good-idea"&gt;comparatively bad track record on availability and regional redundancy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="pt"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;AWS throwing shade at competitors on region vs. availability zones &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reInforce?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#reInforce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/sg36GRjeXC"&gt;pic.twitter.com/sg36GRjeXC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexandre Sieira (@AlexandreSieira) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlexandreSieira/status/1143515510589546496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;25 de junho de 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other one was having a representative from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_One"&gt;Capital One&lt;/a&gt; go on stage to claim they will be entirely cloud-based by 2020. This is a major indication (if you still needed any) of the penetration that cloud adoption is having even on compliance-heavy industries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the many new features and announcements, these were the ones that caught my attention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-vpc-traffic-mirroring/"&gt;VPC Traffic Mirroring&lt;/a&gt;, which is a big deal as this holds the promise of allowing several security product categories to be first-class citizens in AWS. This will mostly benefit mixed environment companies, which will be able to extend the NDR, NIDS or NDLP solutions they already use and love on-prem to cover AWS at least in part. Key caveats of this so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite the name, collection must be set up one &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/using-eni.html"&gt;ENI&lt;/a&gt; at a time. No way to set this up across the entire VPC as you would with &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/userguide/flow-logs.html"&gt;Flow Logs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The replicated traffic generated by each instance will count against the overall bandwidth available to the instance, so do your capacity planning before deploying this in production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2019/06/aws-security-hub-now-generally-available/"&gt;Security Hub is now GA&lt;/a&gt;. Security Hub's main advantage is providing a single dashboard, event format and 3rd party integration point for your AWS security, including native services like Macie and Guard Duty. The main limitation at this point is that even though it has cross-account support, it is a per-region service. So large organizations will still have multiple "panes of glass". Hope to see AWS work on that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kD6JdUAKdV8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2019/06/aws-control-tower-is-now-generally-available/"&gt;Control Tower is now GA&lt;/a&gt;. Basically the story here is that AWS taking the lessons learned from &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/aws-landing-zone/"&gt;Landing Zone&lt;/a&gt;, which is essentially a professional services only offer, and working towards allowing self-service automation of multi-account management native service. At this point it still is very much an MVP with several limitations, but should soon evolve into something invaluable so pay attention to future announcements from this team. Some of the key current limitations:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will only work on new environments and has no way to incorporate an existing &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/organizations/"&gt;Organizations&lt;/a&gt; hierarchy;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does not allow you to create your own service control policies or "guard rails" as they call them in Control Tower lingo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does not allow you to customize provided guard rails ones except for per-account On/Off status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2t-VkWt0rKk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-opt-in-to-default-encryption-for-new-ebs-volumes/"&gt;Opt-in to Default Encryption for EBS Volumes&lt;/a&gt; which should make meeting compliance requirements by default a lot easier on larger organizations. Does not handle existing unencrypted EBS volumes, but then again it's simple enough to find those with &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/encrypted-volumes.html"&gt;Config&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few other resources if you want to learn more about what went on at &lt;a href="https://reinforce.awsevents.com/"&gt;re:Inforce&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLmbt_7-buHq-sx_JFNMsbkI5qHb0gWtfZ"&gt;Youtube playlist with all the recorded sessions&lt;/a&gt; by AWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/reinforce-2019-wrap-up-and-session-links/"&gt;Re:Inforce 2019 wrap-up and session links&lt;/a&gt; by AWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ashishrajan/aws-re-inforce-boston-2019-aws-security-conference-recap-what-they-didnt-tell-you-on-stage-9b7ecc04ddfe"&gt;AWS Re:inforce Boston 2019— AWS Security Conference: Recap (What they didn’t tell you on stage)&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ashishrajan"&gt;Ashish Rajan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="aws"></category><category term="cloud"></category><category term="event"></category><category term="reInforce"></category></entry></feed>